<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>RGSoC Bundler Team Blog</title>
  <subtitle>Women Contributing to Open Source Software</subtitle>
  <id>http://rgsocbundler.github.io/</id>
  <link href="http://rgsocbundler.github.io/"/>
  <link href="http://rgsocbundler.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2013-08-17T01:52:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jen Diamond</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Joyce Hsu</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Jessica Suttles</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Week 5 Day 24 What's Up Doc?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/08/16/week5-day24.html"/>
    <id>/2013/08/16/week5-day24.html</id>
    <published>2013-08-17T01:52:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-08-17T01:52:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RGSoCBundler</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="week-5-day-24"&gt;Week 5 Day 24&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id="whats-up-doc"&gt;What's Up Doc?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id="jens-friday"&gt;Jen's Friday&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I worked on breaking apart the Rationale Page to create a FAQ page. I created a new Get Started page and I created a new Bug report page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="joyces-friday"&gt;Joyce's Friday&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I compared what commands are in the man pages and on the website’s command line reference page. The Bundler commands not listed on the website are &lt;code&gt;bundle help&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;bundle list&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;code&gt;bundle list&lt;/code&gt; does the same thing as &lt;code&gt;bundle show&lt;/code&gt;. I added &lt;code&gt;bundle help&lt;/code&gt; to the command line reference page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I noticed the alignment for the button in the sidebar was off so I made it have even whitespace between the left and right side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the What’s New page, the 1.0 and 1.1 point release buttons link directly to the 1.0 and 1.1 versions of the changelog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="man-pages-and-rake"&gt;Man Pages and Rake&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned that the &lt;a href="http://bundler.io/v1.3/man/bundle.1.html"&gt;Bundler html man pages&lt;/a&gt; were generated with a Rubygem called &lt;a href="http://rubygems.org/gems/ronn"&gt;Ronn&lt;/a&gt;. The html man pages get generated with this command in the bundler repo:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ronn --html man/bundle.ronn
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, a rakefile was created so if we run &lt;code&gt;rake man&lt;/code&gt;, it goes and runs the above command and moves the generated html man pages in the bunder repo into the man directory in our bundler-site repo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I noticed that the bundler-site repo doesn't have a man directory and wondered where the Bundler html man pages were being pulled from. I initially thought the Bundler website was being generated from the bundler-site repo, but with Andre's explanation, it actually is on the gh-pages branch in the bundler repo. We are actually making edits/changes on the bunder-site repo, which then goes to bundler repo on the gh-pages branch where the website is served from. The above steps and creation of the man pages are accomplished with code in the &lt;a href="https://github.com/bundler/bundler-site/blob/master/Rakefile"&gt;Rakefile&lt;/a&gt; where if we run &lt;code&gt;rake release&lt;/code&gt; on the command line, it means the release task will run update_vendor, then build, then man, then release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is similar to how our &lt;a href="http://rgsocbundler.github.io"&gt;rgsocbundler.github.io&lt;/a&gt; website is setup, except it is only on one repo. The website gets edited on the source branch and then &lt;code&gt;rake publish&lt;/code&gt; to go live on the master branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://help.github.com/articles/user-organization-and-project-pages"&gt;How we are allowed to host a website on github.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Week 5 Day 23 What's New &amp; Bug Report</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/08/15/week5-day23.html"/>
    <id>/2013/08/15/week5-day23.html</id>
    <published>2013-08-16T00:53:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-08-16T00:53:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RGSoCBundler</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="week-5-day-23"&gt;Week 5 Day 23&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id="whats-new--bug-report"&gt;What's New &amp;amp; Bug Report&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jessica was Doing Team Building with her G5 team today so Joyce and I worked remotely today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="jens-thursday"&gt;Jen's Thursday&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I worked out of the Starbucks in Atwater Village today. I saw several kids practicing their dance moves outside while waiting for a bus. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I started by creating some issues for some changes I want to make to the Bundler site. Like a create an FAQ page, create a footer and create a Report a Bug page. Then Jessica pointed out that Andre already had posted a Create a Report a Bug issuesn so I decided to work on that first.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I had pulled Joyce's remote to my master branch yesterday so I could view her new sidebar. I was creating my branches with the side bar included until I realized that it was a bad idea so I rolled back and re-created all my branches.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I created a "Report a Bug" page based on the &lt;a href="https://github.com/bundler/bundler/blob/master/ISSUES.md"&gt;ISSUES.md page&lt;/a&gt; I am still getting used to using HAML. White space delimiters are tricky. I sent a pull request for this page so I can get comments on it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I made some comments on the Sidebar pull request Joyce made. I suggested aligning the text left instead of right.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I noticed a link to the bundler-features repo on the issues page. I found the directions to be really unclear in the README. I suggested to Andre that we change it. So he re-wrote it and then I made some more changes to the &lt;a href="https://github.com/bundler/bundler-features"&gt;README file.&lt;/a&gt; I am excited to see that commit merged.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="joyces-thursday"&gt;Joyce's Thursday&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a pull request merged because I didn’t push all my commits right away. Next time I should commit everything before opening a pull request. Or should I?! Since, this turned out to be a nice side effect to a mistake. Hooray!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above merged pull request was actually part of this one to fix open issue 53. I created a new pull request where I added the current What’s New page with buttons and links to new pages for the other Bundler version releases and also linked to the changelog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sidebar was looking uneven and not congruent with the entire page so I made changes to the sass file to make it look nicer and cleaner. I made adjustments to the stylesheet so the whitespace between the left and right side of the page where even, the space between the content and the sidebar where even, the top of the sidebar and the first header was also lined up. Also removed the underline from the sidebar header, made the sidebar header size smaller, and aligned it to the right. The sidebar has turned out looking great!&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Week 5 Day 22 Haml Haml</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/08/14/week5-day22.html"/>
    <id>/2013/08/14/week5-day22.html</id>
    <published>2013-08-15T00:10:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-08-15T00:10:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RGSoCBundler</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="week-5-day-22"&gt;Week 5 Day 22&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id="haml-haml"&gt;Haml Haml&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id="haml"&gt;Haml&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We learned about &lt;a href="http://haml.info/tutorial.html"&gt;Haml&lt;/a&gt; because the Bundler website uses Haml. It can be used instead of ERB and can be converted from an ERB template to Haml. With less syntax, Haml is easier to read and looks clean, some people say it reads like a Haiku.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sidebar was organized and filled with links, which hopefully, makes the website easier to navigate and find what you are looking for. The styling of the sidebar was made to match the current look of the website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a lot of ideas about changes to the Bundler website to make it better. So, we started with making some changes to the homepage and created a Get Started page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We added each other's remote repo to our local repo. That way we can better preview the changes each of us made. (For beginners, don't include the angled brackets)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git remote add &amp;lt;your_nickname&amp;gt; &amp;lt;the_remote_url_link&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To pull down the remote repo to our local repo. We used the same command, but with the &lt;code&gt;nickname&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git fetch &amp;lt;your_nickname&amp;gt;

git merge &amp;lt;your_nickname/the_branch_name&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accidentally added the remote to the wrong repo. To remove a remote repo,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git remote rm &amp;lt;your_nickname&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Week 5 Day 21 Bundler Site</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/08/13/week5-day21.html"/>
    <id>/2013/08/13/week5-day21.html</id>
    <published>2013-08-13T18:32:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-08-13T18:32:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RGSoCBundler</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="week-5-day-21"&gt;Week 5 Day 21&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id="bundler-site"&gt;Bundler Site&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id="the-hub"&gt;The Hub&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today Team Bundler worked in Downtown L.A. at the &lt;a href="http://www.thehubla.com/"&gt;Hub&lt;/a&gt; with the whole G5 crew including Jessicard who is visiting from San Francisco. We worked on the documentation for the &lt;a href="http://bundler.io/"&gt;Bundler&lt;/a&gt; website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="bundler-site-1"&gt;Bundler Site&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jen worked on organizing the content and all the links for the new side bar. We are ready to get rolling and start making changes. Soon we hope it will be much better. There is so much information already there it just needs some organizing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each section will have its own page, Jen found some great information that was buried. The side bar alone will really help make it easier to get around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We looked to improve the documentation for Bundler. Before our trip to the Distill Conference, we had analyzed the website to see what can be better organized and be more user friendly. We browsed through the issues created for the bunder site. The first issue we focused on was making a sidebar for the website. It got confusing between all the syntax; Markdown, Haml, SASS, CSS, and ERB. We got a skeleton of a navigation sidebar on the right side of the page locally and started a pull request for the first piece in creating the sidebar!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="no-jobshttpwwwimdbcomtitlett2357129-"&gt;No &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt2357129/"&gt;jOBs&lt;/a&gt; :(&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After working we all went to try to see the premier of the Steve Jobs movie. We all had printed out our tickets and signed up on the website. We thought all we had to do was stand in line and we'd see it. Little did we know that there was a good chance we wouldn't get in. We stood on the sidewalk collecting friends, Ashley, Anna, Chris, Jessica Suttles, Jessicard, and Shane Becker. After 2 hour of the line slowly surge towards the red carpet we realized that we were 20 people away from getting in. Boo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/bundler-site/bundler.io-screenshot-Aug14-2013.png" alt="Bundler Screenshot" title="Bundler Website Screenshot" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Week 4 Day 19 Distill Day 2</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/08/09/week4-day19.html"/>
    <id>/2013/08/09/week4-day19.html</id>
    <published>2013-08-09T19:15:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-08-09T19:15:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RGSoCBundler</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="week-4-day-19"&gt;Week 4 Day 19&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id="distill-day-2"&gt;Distill Day 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/70981008" width="500" height="281" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://vimeo.com/70981008"&gt;Distill, distilled: The Two Minute Tour&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href="http://vimeo.com/engineyard"&gt;Engine Yard&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="https://vimeo.com"&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="keynote-michael-lopp"&gt;Keynote: Michael Lopp&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Keynote was by Michael Lopp who wrote &lt;em&gt;Being Geek&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Managing Humans&lt;/em&gt;, and worked at Apple for 8 years. Eamon Leonard says it best, &lt;a href="https://blog.engineyard.com/2013/the-thinker-michael-lopp-to-keynote-distill"&gt;"Michael thinks deeply about the problems developers face in their everyday lives, how to help developers identify their true goals, what makes them happy and how to achieve happiness, how to lead and how to follow and much more."&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style="float:left; border: 10px solid #f5f5f5"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/distill/view_treasureisland.jpg" /&gt;&lt;div class="caption"&gt;Nice View of Treasure Island&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id="death-to-cookies---konstantin-haase"&gt;Death to Cookies - Konstantin Haase&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Konstantin Haase is the maintainer of Sinatra and works on Travis CI. We watched Konstantin's talk &lt;a href="https://speakerdeck.com/rkh/distill-death-to-cookies"&gt;Death to Cookies&lt;/a&gt; He taught us that cookies can be poisonous, how cookies can be spoofed, and showed us ways to use them safely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style="clear: both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id="function-and-dysfunction-in-engineering-driven-cultures---shanley-kane"&gt;Function and Dysfunction in Engineering-Driven Cultures - Shanley Kane&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shanely Kane used fairy tales to juxtapose engineering culture and how tech decisions are shaped by rewards, values, power, homogeneity, and team history. She talked about racism, classism, and sexism in the tech fields and how we can get past that through hiring diversity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style="float:right; border: 10px solid #f5f5f5"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/distill/Picnic_Lunch.jpg" /&gt;&lt;div class="caption"&gt;Picnic Lunch&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id="lunch-and-lawn-games"&gt;Lunch and Lawn Games&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had lunch with Marcy, Elise, Dave and Cal. We talked about &lt;a href="http://evankozierachi.com/uploads/The_Plague_by_Albert_Camus.pdf"&gt;Camu's the Plague&lt;/a&gt;. Dave talked about his experience teaching programming in Texas and future technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lunch we talked to Konstantine about his Rails Girls team the Inchworms. He told us about all the great work they are doing in Sinatra and about their &lt;a href="http://railsgirlsberlin.de/workshops/projectgroups/"&gt;project groups&lt;/a&gt; they were in before Rails Girls Summer of Code started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style="clear: both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id="full-stack-documentation"&gt;Full Stack Documentation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id="a-holistic-approach-to-documentation-testing-development-and-deployment---ana-nelson"&gt;A holistic approach to documentation, testing, development and deployment - Ana Nelson&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fKiuHJ-MUzg"&gt;Slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ana Nelson is the creator of Dexy, a Python-based tool for documentation. Documentation is incredibly important as part of best practice to get the most value out of your code. Ana talked about the tools for integrating code and prose.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Week 4 Day 18 Distill Day 1</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/08/08/week4-day18.html"/>
    <id>/2013/08/08/week4-day18.html</id>
    <published>2013-08-08T19:15:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-08-08T19:15:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RGSoCBundler</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="week-4-day-18"&gt;Week 4 Day 18&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id="distill-day-1"&gt;Distill Day 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We left the beautiful Hilton hotel on a bus bound for Treasure Island which is just off the Bay Bridge. We had a great view from the bus of the Golden Gate bridge and the bay below. We arrived at The Winery, where Distill was held, to an amazing spread of breakfast treats and hand poured coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We finally met our mentor Andre Arko and he came bearing gifts in the form of bright blue Bundler t-shirts!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We used the Twitter hashtag #distill13 to post about the adventures of the day. Real-time tweets were posted on the screen in the main room for everyone to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="keynote-nolan-and-brent-bushnell"&gt;Keynote: Nolan and Brent Bushnell&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The keynote address was given by the founder of Atari and Chucky Cheese, Nolan Bushnell, and his son Brent Bushnell who runs Two Bit Circus in Los Angeles which is a group that helps children learn programming through the making of amusements. They were vibrant, inspiring speakers concentrating on pushing yourself to create and complete projects. Jen had the pleasure of meeting with them at lunch. She had previously met Brent Bushnell in Los Angeles at his amazing workspace in the Brewery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style="float: left; border:10px solid white"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/distill/jinas_talk.jpg" /&gt;&lt;div class="caption"&gt;Jina Bolton speaking at the Distill Conference&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id="realigning--refactoring-ui---jina-bolton"&gt;Realigning &amp;amp; Refactoring UI - Jina Bolton&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Product Designer at Do&lt;/strong&gt; // &lt;a href="http://de.slideshare.net/Codemotion/ui-realigning-refactoring-by-jina-bolton"&gt;Slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jina talked about her favorite CSS tools to use in web development. She impressed upon the crowd to not refactor everything all at once, but "do refactor going forward." She had a light, friendly style of speaking that made her easy to listen to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="connascence-examined---jim-weirich"&gt;Connascence Examined - Jim Weirich&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chief Scientist at @neo_innovation, Ruby Enthusiast, Clojure dabbler onestepback.org&lt;/strong&gt; // &lt;a href="http://youtu.be/HQXVKHoUQxY"&gt;Slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jim defined connascence between relationships between different Name, Type, Meaning, Position, Timing, and Execution. In the second part, he talked about using Ruby to control Drones and showed video of it. Jen spoke with Jim Weirich and Ron Evans at lunch about drones, Kids Ruby, and music. Jim played a few songs on his ukulele.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notes: &lt;a href="https://www.purdue.edu/apps/account/IAMO/I2A2/Reference/Purdue_I2A2_Luhn.jsp"&gt;luhn_check&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://plato.stanford.edu/entries/supervenience/"&gt;supervenience&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style="float: right; border:10px solid white"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/distill/JimWeirich_Ukulele.jpg" /&gt;&lt;div class="caption"&gt;Jim Weirich playing his Ukulele at Lunch&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id="lunch-and-lawn-games"&gt;Lunch and Lawn Games&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had an amazing picnic lunch with the backdrop of San Francisco, Engine Yard's Panda mascot and lawn games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="keynote-james-whelton"&gt;Keynote: James Whelton&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Co-Founder of CoderDojo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He gave an inspiring talk about why he started CoderDojo. He wanted to start a program for kids that he wished existed when he started learning to program. His program started in Ireland and has spread to include Dojo's all over the world. Later in the day, James gave Joyce a pep talk to feel less nervous about the lightning talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="history-of-women-in-programming---elise-worthy--jessica-lynn-suttles"&gt;History of Women in Programming - Elise Worthy &amp;amp; Jessica Lynn Suttles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elise Worthy - Founder of Brandworthy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jessica Suttles - Software Engineer of G5&lt;/strong&gt; // &lt;a href="https://speakerdeck.com/jlsuttles/women-and-computing-at-distill"&gt;Slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jessica and Elise gave their last presentation of this talk. Since we saw it at the LA Ruby Monthly Meetup, they've added more information and slides and really had their talk down to a science. Everyone was intrigued by the importance of women's contribution to programming that they pointed out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="lightning-talks"&gt;Lightning Talks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://speakerdeck.com/jendiamond/distill-rails-girls-summer-of-code-lightning-talk-by-jen-diamond-and-joyce-hsu"&gt;Slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8 of us were selected for the lightning talk. The other lightning speakers were Brenton Cheng, Jon Hyman, Dave Cadwallader, Kevin Stevens, Denis Ivanov, and Kyle Henderson. Then, Jim Weirich played a great song on his ukulele about God writing in Lisp. Giving the lightning talk to about 200 people was a great milestone. We talked about what Rails Girls does and the transition to Summer of Code, what we have learned so far, our plans for the future, and where to follow our progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="pre-moonshine"&gt;Pre-Moonshine&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had dinner with everyone from Team Bundler and friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="moonshine"&gt;Moonshine&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moonshine was the kick-off party at the Old Mint in SF. We took fun pictures with costumes, socialized, and wandered around taking in the history of coin making and San Francisco. There was a candy room, vaults, projections, a DJ, and plenty of swag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/distill/jen_diamond-joyce_distill.jpg" alt="Jen Diamond and Joyce Hsu giving their Ligthning talk about Rails Girls Summer of Code at the Distill Conference in San Francisco" title="Jen Diamond and Joyce Hsu giving their Ligthning talk about Rails Girls Summer of Code at the Distill Conference in San Francisco" /&gt;
Jen Diamond and Joyce Hsu giving their Ligthning talk about Rails Girls Summer of Code at the Distill Conference in San Francisco.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
