<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>RGSoC Bundler Team Blog</title>
  <subtitle>Women Contributing to Open Source Software</subtitle>
  <id>http://rgsocbundler.github.io/</id>
  <link href="http://rgsocbundler.github.io/"/>
  <link href="http://rgsocbundler.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2013-08-13T18:32:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jen Diamond</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Joyce Hsu</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Jessica Suttles</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Week 5 Day 21 Bundler Site</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/08/13/week5-day21.html"/>
    <id>/2013/08/13/week5-day21.html</id>
    <published>2013-08-13T18:32:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-08-13T18:32:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RGSoCBundler</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="week-5-day-21"&gt;Week 5 Day 21&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id="bundler-site"&gt;Bundler Site&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id="the-hub"&gt;The Hub&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today Team Bundler worked in Downtown L.A. at the &lt;a href="http://www.thehubla.com/"&gt;Hub&lt;/a&gt; with the whole G5 crew including Jessicard who is visiting from San Francisco. We worked on the documentation for the &lt;a href="http://bundler.io/"&gt;Bundler&lt;/a&gt; website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="bundler-site-1"&gt;Bundler Site&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jen worked on organizing the content and all the links for the new side bar. We are ready to get rolling and start making changes. Soon we hope it will be much better. There is so much information already there it just needs some organizing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each section will have its own page, Jen found some great information that was buried. The side bar alone will really help make it easier to get around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We looked to improve the documentation for Bundler. Before our trip to the Distill Conference, we had analyzed the website to see what can be better organized and be more user friendly. We browsed through the issues created for the bunder site. The first issue we focused on was making a sidebar for the website. It got confusing between all the syntax; Markdown, Haml, SASS, CSS, and ERB. We got a skeleton of a navigation sidebar on the right side of the page locally and started a pull request for the first piece in creating the sidebar!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="no-jobshttpwwwimdbcomtitlett2357129-"&gt;No &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt2357129/"&gt;jOBs&lt;/a&gt; :(&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After working we all went to try to see the premier of the Steve Jobs movie. We all had printed out our tickets and signed up on the website. We thought all we had to do was stand in line and we'd see it. Little did we know that there was a good chance we wouldn't get in. We stood on the sidewalk collecting friends, Ashley, Anna, Chris, Jessica Suttles, Jessicard, and Shane Becker. After 2 hour of the line slowly surge towards the red carpet we realized that we were 20 people away from getting in. Boo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/bundler-site/bundler.io-screenshot-Aug14-2013.png" alt="Bundler Screenshot" title="Bundler Website Screenshot" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Week 4 Day 19 Distill Day 2</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/08/09/week4-day19.html"/>
    <id>/2013/08/09/week4-day19.html</id>
    <published>2013-08-09T19:15:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-08-09T19:15:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RGSoCBundler</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="week-4-day-19"&gt;Week 4 Day 19&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id="distill-day-2"&gt;Distill Day 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/70981008" width="500" height="281" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://vimeo.com/70981008"&gt;Distill, distilled: The Two Minute Tour&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href="http://vimeo.com/engineyard"&gt;Engine Yard&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="https://vimeo.com"&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="keynote-michael-lopp"&gt;Keynote: Michael Lopp&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Keynote was by Michael Lopp who wrote &lt;em&gt;Being Geek&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Managing Humans&lt;/em&gt;, and worked at Apple for 8 years. Eamon Leonard says it best, &lt;a href="https://blog.engineyard.com/2013/the-thinker-michael-lopp-to-keynote-distill"&gt;"Michael thinks deeply about the problems developers face in their everyday lives, how to help developers identify their true goals, what makes them happy and how to achieve happiness, how to lead and how to follow and much more."&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style="float:left; border: 10px solid #f5f5f5"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/distill/view_treasureisland.jpg" /&gt;&lt;div class="caption"&gt;Nice View of Treasure Island&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id="death-to-cookies---konstantin-haase"&gt;Death to Cookies - Konstantin Haase&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Konstantin Haase is the maintainer of Sinatra and works on Travis CI. We watched Konstantin's talk &lt;a href="https://speakerdeck.com/rkh/distill-death-to-cookies"&gt;Death to Cookies&lt;/a&gt; He taught us that cookies can be poisonous, how cookies can be spoofed, and showed us ways to use them safely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style="clear: both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id="function-and-dysfunction-in-engineering-driven-cultures---shanley-kane"&gt;Function and Dysfunction in Engineering-Driven Cultures - Shanley Kane&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shanely Kane used fairy tales to juxtapose engineering culture and how tech decisions are shaped by rewards, values, power, homogeneity, and team history. She talked about racism, classism, and sexism in the tech fields and how we can get past that through hiring diversity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style="float:right; border: 10px solid #f5f5f5"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/distill/Picnic_Lunch.jpg" /&gt;&lt;div class="caption"&gt;Picnic Lunch&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id="lunch-and-lawn-games"&gt;Lunch and Lawn Games&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had lunch with Marcy, Elise, Dave and Cal. We talked about &lt;a href="http://evankozierachi.com/uploads/The_Plague_by_Albert_Camus.pdf"&gt;Camu's the Plague&lt;/a&gt;. Dave talked about his experience teaching programming in Texas and future technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lunch we talked to Konstantine about his Rails Girls team the Inchworms. He told us about all the great work they are doing in Sinatra and about their &lt;a href="http://railsgirlsberlin.de/workshops/projectgroups/"&gt;project groups&lt;/a&gt; they were in before Rails Girls Summer of Code started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style="clear: both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id="full-stack-documentation"&gt;Full Stack Documentation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id="a-holistic-approach-to-documentation-testing-development-and-deployment---ana-nelson"&gt;A holistic approach to documentation, testing, development and deployment - Ana Nelson&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fKiuHJ-MUzg"&gt;Slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ana Nelson is the creator of Dexy, a Python-based tool for documentation. Documentation is incredibly important as part of best practice to get the most value out of your code. Ana talked about the tools for integrating code and prose.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Week 4 Day 18 Distill Day 1</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/08/08/week4-day18.html"/>
    <id>/2013/08/08/week4-day18.html</id>
    <published>2013-08-08T19:15:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-08-08T19:15:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RGSoCBundler</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="week-4-day-18"&gt;Week 4 Day 18&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id="distill-day-1"&gt;Distill Day 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We left the beautiful Hilton hotel on a bus bound for Treasure Island which is just off the Bay Bridge. We had a great view from the bus of the Golden Gate bridge and the bay below. We arrived at The Winery, where Distill was held, to an amazing spread of breakfast treats and hand poured coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We finally met our mentor Andre Arko and he came bearing gifts in the form of bright blue Bundler t-shirts!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We used the Twitter hashtag #distill13 to post about the adventures of the day. Real-time tweets were posted on the screen in the main room for everyone to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="keynote-nolan-and-brent-bushnell"&gt;Keynote: Nolan and Brent Bushnell&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The keynote address was given by the founder of Atari and Chucky Cheese, Nolan Bushnell, and his son Brent Bushnell who runs Two Bit Circus in Los Angeles which is a group that helps children learn programming through the making of amusements. They were vibrant, inspiring speakers concentrating on pushing yourself to create and complete projects. Jen had the pleasure of meeting with them at lunch. She had previously met Brent Bushnell in Los Angeles at his amazing workspace in the Brewery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style="float: left; border:10px solid white"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/distill/jinas_talk.jpg" /&gt;&lt;div class="caption"&gt;Jina Bolton speaking at the Distill Conference&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id="realigning--refactoring-ui---jina-bolton"&gt;Realigning &amp;amp; Refactoring UI - Jina Bolton&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Product Designer at Do&lt;/strong&gt; // &lt;a href="http://de.slideshare.net/Codemotion/ui-realigning-refactoring-by-jina-bolton"&gt;Slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jina talked about her favorite CSS tools to use in web development. She impressed upon the crowd to not refactor everything all at once, but "do refactor going forward." She had a light, friendly style of speaking that made her easy to listen to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="connascence-examined---jim-weirich"&gt;Connascence Examined - Jim Weirich&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chief Scientist at @neo_innovation, Ruby Enthusiast, Clojure dabbler onestepback.org&lt;/strong&gt; // &lt;a href="http://youtu.be/HQXVKHoUQxY"&gt;Slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jim defined connascence between relationships between different Name, Type, Meaning, Position, Timing, and Execution. In the second part, he talked about using Ruby to control Drones and showed video of it. Jen spoke with Jim Weirich and Ron Evans at lunch about drones, Kids Ruby, and music. Jim played a few songs on his ukulele.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notes: &lt;a href="https://www.purdue.edu/apps/account/IAMO/I2A2/Reference/Purdue_I2A2_Luhn.jsp"&gt;luhn_check&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://plato.stanford.edu/entries/supervenience/"&gt;supervenience&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style="float: right; border:10px solid white"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/distill/JimWeirich_Ukulele.jpg" /&gt;&lt;div class="caption"&gt;Jim Weirich playing his Ukulele at Lunch&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id="lunch-and-lawn-games"&gt;Lunch and Lawn Games&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had an amazing picnic lunch with the backdrop of San Francisco, Engine Yard's Panda mascot and lawn games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="keynote-james-whelton"&gt;Keynote: James Whelton&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Co-Founder of CoderDojo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He gave an inspiring talk about why he started CoderDojo. He wanted to start a program for kids that he wished existed when he started learning to program. His program started in Ireland and has spread to include Dojo's all over the world. Later in the day, James gave Joyce a pep talk to feel less nervous about the lightning talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="history-of-women-in-programming---elise-worthy--jessica-lynn-suttles"&gt;History of Women in Programming - Elise Worthy &amp;amp; Jessica Lynn Suttles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elise Worthy - Founder of Brandworthy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jessica Suttles - Software Engineer of G5&lt;/strong&gt; // &lt;a href="https://speakerdeck.com/jlsuttles/women-and-computing-at-distill"&gt;Slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jessica and Elise gave their last presentation of this talk. Since we saw it at the LA Ruby Monthly Meetup, they've added more information and slides and really had their talk down to a science. Everyone was intrigued by the importance of women's contribution to programming that they pointed out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="lightning-talks"&gt;Lightning Talks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://speakerdeck.com/jendiamond/distill-rails-girls-summer-of-code-lightning-talk-by-jen-diamond-and-joyce-hsu"&gt;Slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8 of us were selected for the lightning talk. The other lightning speakers were Brenton Cheng, Jon Hyman, Dave Cadwallader, Kevin Stevens, Denis Ivanov, and Kyle Henderson. Then, Jim Weirich played a great song on his ukulele about God writing in Lisp. Giving the lightning talk to about 200 people was a great milestone. We talked about what Rails Girls does and the transition to Summer of Code, what we have learned so far, our plans for the future, and where to follow our progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="pre-moonshine"&gt;Pre-Moonshine&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had dinner with everyone from Team Bundler and friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="moonshine"&gt;Moonshine&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moonshine was the kick-off party at the Old Mint in SF. We took fun pictures with costumes, socialized, and wandered around taking in the history of coin making and San Francisco. There was a candy room, vaults, projections, a DJ, and plenty of swag.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Week 4 Day 17 Friscoooo</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/08/07/week4-day17.html"/>
    <id>/2013/08/07/week4-day17.html</id>
    <published>2013-08-07T18:45:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-08-07T18:45:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RGSoCBundler</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="week-4-day-17"&gt;Week 4 Day 17&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id="how-i-love-ya-friscoooo"&gt;How I love ya, Friscoooo&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All 3 of us flew to &lt;a href="http://youtu.be/WnjufR8GDcw"&gt;San Francisco&lt;/a&gt; today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Jessica attended a speaker's dinner we went to &lt;a href="http://www.curryupnow.com/menus"&gt;Curry Up Now&lt;/a&gt; in the Mission then we saw the band &lt;a href="http://www.gauchojazz.com/about.html"&gt;Gaucho&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href="http://amnesiathebar.com/newp/"&gt;Amnesia&lt;/a&gt; Here's their &lt;a href="https://myspace.com/gauchosf"&gt;myspace&lt;/a&gt; Their sax player plays with Tom Waits. We soaked up culture and inspiration San Francisco style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www3.hilton.com/en/hotels/california/hilton-san-francisco-union-square-SFOFHHH/index.html"&gt;The Hilton&lt;/a&gt; where we are staying is beautiful and the rooms are so comfortable and posh. Thanks Distill, Engine Yard and Rails Girls Summer of Code! We are so ready for the conference tomorrow. There are so many interesting talks to attend.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Week 4 Day 16 Documentation</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/08/06/week4-day16.html"/>
    <id>/2013/08/06/week4-day16.html</id>
    <published>2013-08-07T00:03:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-08-07T00:03:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RGSoCBundler</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="week-4-day-16"&gt;Week 4 Day 16&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id="documentation"&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we started working on improving the documentation on the &lt;a href="http://bundler.io/"&gt;Bundler website.&lt;/a&gt; We all agree that the site needs better navigation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="jens-tuesday"&gt;Jen's Tuesday&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went through every page of the Bundler site testing buttons, links and identifing problems with the structuring of the information. I found a 404 error buried in the site. &lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/jendiamond/6169493#file-gistfile1-md"&gt;My notes.&lt;/a&gt; I also fixed the slide presentation for our possible talk at Distill tomorrow. I really hope that happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="joyce-tuesday"&gt;Joyce' Tuesday&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went through the google analytics of the Bundler site and gave recommendations and suggestion based on my findings.
Looks like the first button people click on is &lt;strong&gt;Learn More: Gemfile&lt;/strong&gt; I wonder if others did the same. I initially browsed right past &lt;strong&gt;Would you like to: Get started, Report a bug, See what's new, Read documentation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="distill"&gt;Distill&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are both really excited for our first Ruby Conference in San Francisco tomorrow at &lt;a href="http://distill.engineyard.com/"&gt;Distill.&lt;/a&gt; We get to watch Jessic give her talk and a bunch of other really interesting speakers. We also get to meet our mentor Andre in person. Oh yeah, Andre is going to send us/ bring us? Bundler shirts!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Week 4 Day 15 Ruby Warrior</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/08/05/week4-day15.html"/>
    <id>/2013/08/05/week4-day15.html</id>
    <published>2013-08-06T00:45:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-08-06T00:45:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RGSoCBundler</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2 id="week-4-day-15"&gt;Week 4 Day 15&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id="ruby-warrior"&gt;Ruby Warrior&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.bloc.io/ruby-warrior"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/rubywarriors-img.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We played &lt;a href="https://www.bloc.io/ruby-warrior"&gt;Ruby Warrior&lt;/a&gt; to learn the Ruby language in a fun and interactive way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jen got her Rspec test to pass for her gem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We practiced our lightning talk for the Distill Conference on Aug 8-9.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
