<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>RGSoC Bundler Team Blog</title>
  <subtitle>Women Contributing to Open Source Software</subtitle>
  <id>http://rgsocbundler.github.io/</id>
  <link href="http://rgsocbundler.github.io/"/>
  <link href="http://rgsocbundler.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2013-08-08T19:15:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jen Diamond</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Joyce Hsu</name>
  </author>
  <author>
    <name>Jessica Suttles</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Week 4 Day 18 Distill Day 1</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/08/08/week4-day18.html"/>
    <id>/2013/08/08/week4-day18.html</id>
    <published>2013-08-08T19:15:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-08-08T19:15:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RGSoCBundler</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="week-4-day-18"&gt;Week 4 Day 18&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id="distill-day-1"&gt;Distill Day 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We left the beautiful Hilton hotel on a bus bound for Treasure Island which is just off the Bay Bridge. We had a great view from the bus of the Golden Gate bridge and the bay below. We arrived at The Distillery, where Distill was held, to an amazing spread of breakfast treats and hand poured coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We used the Twitter hashtag #distill13 to post about the adventures of the day. Real-time tweets were posted on the screen in the main room for everyone to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="keynote-nolan-and-brent-bushnell"&gt;Keynote: Nolan and Brent Bushnell&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The keynote address was given by the founder of Atari and Chucky Cheese, Nolan Bushnell, and his son Brent Bushnell who runs Two Bit Circus in Los Angeles which is a group that helps children learn programming through the making of amusements. They were vibrant, inspiring speakers concentrating on pushing yourself to create and complete projects. Jen had the pleasure of meeting with them at lunch. She had previously met Brent Bushnell in Los Angeles at his amazing workspace in the Brewery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="realigning--refactoring-ui---jina-bolton"&gt;Realigning &amp;amp; Refactoring UI - Jina Bolton&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Product Designer at Do&lt;/strong&gt; // &lt;a href="http://de.slideshare.net/Codemotion/ui-realigning-refactoring-by-jina-bolton"&gt;Slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jina talked about her favorite CSS tools to use in web development. She impressed upon the crowd to not refactor everything all at once, but "do refactor going forward." She had a light, friendly style of speaking that made her easy to listen to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="connascence-examined---jim-weirich"&gt;Connascence Examined - Jim Weirich&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chief Scientist at @neo_innovation, Ruby Enthusiast, Clojure dabbler onestepback.org&lt;/strong&gt; // &lt;a href="http://youtu.be/HQXVKHoUQxY"&gt;Slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jim defined connascence between relationships between different Name, Type, Meaning, Position, Timing, and Execution. In the second part, he talked about using Ruby to control Drones and showed video of it. Jen spoke with Jim Weirich and Ron Evans at lunch about drones, Kids Ruby, and music. Jim played a few songs on his ukulele.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notes: &lt;a href="https://www.purdue.edu/apps/account/IAMO/I2A2/Reference/Purdue_I2A2_Luhn.jsp"&gt;luhn_check&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://plato.stanford.edu/entries/supervenience/"&gt;supervenience&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="lunch-and-lawn-games"&gt;Lunch and Lawn Games&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had an amazing picnic lunch with the backdrop of San Francisco, Engine Yard's Panda mascot and lawn games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="keynote-james-whelton"&gt;Keynote: James Whelton&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Co-Founder of CoderDojo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He gave an inspiring talk about why he started CoderDojo. He wanted to start a program for kids that he wished existed when he started learning to program. His program started in Ireland and has spread to include Dojo's all over the world. Later in the day, James gave Joyce a pep talk to feel less nervous about the lightning talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="history-of-women-in-programming---elise-worthy--jessica-lynn-suttles"&gt;History of Women in Programming - Elise Worthy &amp;amp; Jessica Lynn Suttles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elise Worthy - Founder of Brandworthy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jessica Suttles - Software Engineer of G5&lt;/strong&gt; // &lt;a href="https://speakerdeck.com/jlsuttles/women-and-computing-at-distill"&gt;Slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jessica and Elise gave their last presentation of this talk. Since we saw it at the LA Ruby Monthly Meetup, they've added more information and slides and really had their talk down to a science. Everyone was intrigued by the importance of women's contribution to programming that they pointed out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="lightning-talks"&gt;Lightning Talks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://speakerdeck.com/jendiamond/distill-rails-girls-summer-of-code-lightning-talk-by-jen-diamond-and-joyce-hsu"&gt;Slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8 of us were selected for the lightning talk. The other lightning speakers were Brenton Cheng, Jon Hyman, Dave Cadwallader, Kevin Stevens, Denis Ivanov, and Kyle Henderson. Then, Jim Weirich played a great song on his ukulele about God writing in Lisp. Giving the lightning talk to about 200 people was a great milestone. We talked about what Rails Girls does and the transition to Summer of Code, what we have learned so far, our plans for the future, and where to follow our progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="moonshine"&gt;Moonshine&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moonshine was the kick-off party at the Old Mint in SF. We took fun pictures with costumes, socialized, and wandered around taking in the history of coin making and San Francisco. There was a candy room, vaults, projections, a DJ, and plenty of swag.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Week 4 Day 15 Friscoooo</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/08/08/week5-day17.html"/>
    <id>/2013/08/08/week5-day17.html</id>
    <published>2013-08-08T18:45:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-08-08T18:45:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RGSoCBundler</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="week-4-day-17"&gt;Week 4 Day 17&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id="how-i-love-ya-friscoooo"&gt;How I love ya, Friscoooo&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All 3 of us flew to &lt;a href="http://youtu.be/WnjufR8GDcw"&gt;San Francisco&lt;/a&gt; today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Jessica attended a speaker's dinner we went to &lt;a href="http://www.curryupnow.com/menus"&gt;Curry Up Now&lt;/a&gt; in the Mission then we saw the band &lt;a href="http://www.gauchojazz.com/about.html"&gt;Gaucho&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href="http://amnesiathebar.com/newp/"&gt;Amnesia&lt;/a&gt; Here's their myspace(https://myspace.com/gauchosf)  Culture and inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://www3.hilton.com/en/hotels/california/hilton-san-francisco-union-square-SFOFHHH/index.html"&gt;hotel&lt;/a&gt; is beautiful and the rooms are so comfortable and posh. Thanks Distill, Engine Yard and Rails Girls Summer of Code! We are so ready for the conference tomorrow. There are so many interesting talks to attend.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Week 4 Day 16 Documentation</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/08/07/week4-day16.html"/>
    <id>/2013/08/07/week4-day16.html</id>
    <published>2013-08-08T00:03:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-08-08T00:03:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RGSoCBundler</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="week-4-day-16"&gt;Week 4 Day 16&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id="documentation"&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we started working on improving the documentation on the &lt;a href="http://bundler.io/"&gt;Bundler website.&lt;/a&gt; We all agree that the site needs better navigation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="jens-tuesday"&gt;Jen's Tuesday&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went through every page of the Bundler site testing buttons, links and identifing problems with the structuring of the information. I found a 404 error buried in the site. &lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/jendiamond/6169493#file-gistfile1-md"&gt;My notes.&lt;/a&gt; I also fixed the slide presentation for our possible talk at Distill tomorrow. I really hope that happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="joyce-tuesday"&gt;Joyce' Tuesday&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went through the google analytics of the Bundler site and gave recommendations and suggestion based on my findings.
Looks like the first button people click on is &lt;strong&gt;Learn More: Gemfile&lt;/strong&gt; I wonder if others did the same. I initially browsed right past &lt;strong&gt;Would you like to: Get started, Report a bug, See what's new, Read documentation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="distill"&gt;Distill&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are both really excited for our first Ruby Conference in San Francisco tomorrow at &lt;a href="http://distill.engineyard.com/"&gt;Distill.&lt;/a&gt; We get to watch Jessic give her talk and a bunch of other really interesting speakers. We also get to meet our mentor Andre in person. Oh yeah, Andre is going to send us/ bring us? Bundler shirts!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Week 4 Day 15 Ruby Warrior</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/08/05/week4-day15.html"/>
    <id>/2013/08/05/week4-day15.html</id>
    <published>2013-08-06T00:45:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-08-06T00:45:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RGSoCBundler</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2 id="week-4-day-15"&gt;Week 4 Day 15&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id="ruby-warrior"&gt;Ruby Warrior&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.bloc.io/ruby-warrior"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/rubywarriors-img.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We played &lt;a href="https://www.bloc.io/ruby-warrior"&gt;Ruby Warrior&lt;/a&gt; to learn the Ruby language in a fun and interactive way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jen got her Rspec test to pass for her gem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We practiced our lightning talk for the Distill Conference on Aug 8-9.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Week 3 Day 14 More Gem Production and Testing</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/08/02/week3-day14.html"/>
    <id>/2013/08/02/week3-day14.html</id>
    <published>2013-08-03T01:17:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-08-03T01:17:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RGSoCBundler</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2 id="more-gem-production-and-testing"&gt;More Gem Production and Testing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://d33y93cfm0wb4z.cloudfront.net/Lauren/Homepage_Images/Gems_and_birthmonth.jpg" alt="Alt gems" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were both reading about Rspec in the Pragmatic Programmer's &lt;strong&gt;The RSpec Book&lt;/strong&gt; (Behaviour-Driven Development with RSpec, Cucumber, and Friends) by David Chelimsky&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also were looking at Peepcode's Rspec Screencast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="jens-friday"&gt;Jen's Friday&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I worked on my gem last night at the Ruby Study Group and I swear it was working. This morning I ran it and ERROR. I tried so many different things to fix it that I finally lost the thread. I decided to just go through our tutorial and create it again from scratch but there are definitely some missing parts we need to fill in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent some more time in my .bashrc file. Apparently I have become obsessed with it. My problem was that it was hard to read my errors because my prompt was the same color as everything else so it all blurred together. I used a combination of this site: https://wiki.archlinux.org/index.php/Color_Bash_Prompt and this site: http://ubuntugenius.wordpress.com/2011/07/11/how-to-change-the-command-line-prompt-colour-in-the-ubuntulinux-terminal/ and the Terminal's Profile Preferences a. Hooray, it is finally readable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="joyces-friday"&gt;Joyce's Friday&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read the Rspec and bdd page on jumpstartlab’s website. I worked on a rspec test to pass for the Lorem gem with the help of Jessica Suttles and Andre Arko. I assumed I wrote the test wrong and didn’t really look at the error messages. With their help, going over the 2 failures that came up, I got a test to pass. Yay. I had glossed and skimmed the test, which led to reading on how to read error messages. :sweat_smile:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="our-resources"&gt;Our Resources&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rspec&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;http://tutorials.jumpstartlab.com/topics/internal_testing/rspec_and_bdd.html&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;http://it-ebooks.info/book/77/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Understanding Error Messages&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/17749403/how-do-i-read-error-messages-in-ruby-and-ruby-on-rails&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;http://philcrissman.com/2010/11/08/how-to-read-error-messages-for-ruby-on-rails/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;http://modernlegend.github.io/blog/2013/02/28/how-to-read-ruby-errors/&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Week 3 Day 13 Namespace n Rspec</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2013/08/02/week3-day13.html"/>
    <id>/2013/08/02/week3-day13.html</id>
    <published>2013-08-02T18:28:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-08-02T18:28:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>RGSoCBundler</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="week-3-day-11"&gt;Week 3 Day 11&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id="namespace-n-rspec"&gt;Namespace n Rspec&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id="what-we-did"&gt;What We Did&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We fixed our gem to have namespace in the &lt;code&gt;lib/loremz/cli.rb&lt;/code&gt;. Namespace is where the class CLI is encapsulated by module Loremz. The syntax for namespacing is &lt;code&gt;Loremz::CLI&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;module Loremz
  class CLI &amp;lt; Thor
    #your methods
  end
end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That way our &lt;code&gt;lib/loremz/cli.rb&lt;/code&gt; file matches with the &lt;code&gt;lib/loremz.rb&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why do we want our &lt;code&gt;lib/loremz/cli.rb&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;lib/loremz.rb&lt;/code&gt; file to match?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;lib/loremz/cli.rb&lt;/code&gt; file is just for handling what comes in the command line. While the content would be stored in the &lt;code&gt;lib/loremz.rb&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We use &lt;code&gt;lib/loremz/cli.rb&lt;/code&gt; to call &lt;code&gt;lib/loremz.rb&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we also worked on writing RSpec tests for the gem we created.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="what-we-learned-from-our-boo-boos"&gt;What We Learned from our Boo Boo’s?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joyce's ipsum command didn't work because the &lt;code&gt;require "loremz"&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;lib/loremz/cli.rb&lt;/code&gt; was left out. We need to include it to load the file &lt;code&gt;lib/loremz.rb&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
